<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mudasir&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://mudasir.co/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mudasir&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mudasir</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 16:22:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mudasir.co/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crowdstrike Outage</title>
      <link>https://mudasir.co/en/posts/crowd_strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 16:22:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mudasir.co/en/posts/crowd_strike/</guid>
      <description>What exactly happened with #Crowdstrike outage Programmer Error A #CrowdStrike developer made a mistake while writing code in C++.&#xA;Null Pointer Creation The code created a pointer variable (Obj* obj) that should have pointed to a specific object in memory containing data. However, due to the error, the pointer remained NULL - meaning it wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually pointing to any valid memory location.&#xA;Missing Null Check The code tried to use this null pointer (obj) to access information within the object it was supposed to represent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Combine</title>
      <link>https://mudasir.co/en/posts/catalogs-in-ua-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 13:39:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mudasir.co/en/posts/catalogs-in-ua-kit/</guid>
      <description>Core Concepts There are only a few core concepts that you need to know to use Combine effectively, but they are very important to understand. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example:&#xA;- Publisher and Subscriber - Opertators - Subjects Publisher &amp;amp; Subscriber What is a Publisher A publisher provides data when available and upon request. A publisher that has not had any subscription requests will not provide any data. These are often written using the generics syntax which uses the &amp;lt; and &amp;gt; symbol around text describing the types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mudasir.co/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mudasir.co/en/about/</guid>
      <description>Mudasir Ahmed - Software Engineer at ❤️, Manager by Day About Me I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer with ~15 years of experience. I have a 4-year degree in Computer Science and 2-years Masters&#xA;Skills and Achievements Can solve and implement algorithms quickly, even the really hard ones Developed a wide variety of highly scalable applications using AWS Familiar with concepts from &amp;ldquo;Designing Data Intensive Applications&amp;rdquo; Focus on Backend, but spent half of my career using iOS, Android Career History United Airlines - 4 years Kin+Carta - 2 year HP - 8 year Education American University Degree: Computer Science GPA: 3.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
